Daniel Byrd

16 King Eider Way, Taylors, SC 29687

Cell Phone: 864-363-7021

daniel.byrd2@charter.net

Help Desk Analyst • Computer Programmer • Web Designer • Digital Artist

Professional Profile

Help desk analyst with two plus years of experience and a junior programmer looking to utilize skills I have learned over the past several years to help others become more productive, enhance user experiences, and provide value to the business and their partners. I am a motivated self-starter, actively working to improve my skills and open to learning new technologies. You can view some the projects I have worked on in the past on my online portfolio found at: http://dbyrdportfolio.atwebpages.com

Areas of Expertise

Languages: C#, C++, Java, SQL, PHP

Web Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ASP.Net

Tools: Service Now, SQL Server Reporting Services, SQL Server Integration Services, Telerik Tools,

Microsoft Office: Word, Excel, and PowerPoint

Azure Devops (for source control)

Professional Experience:

Level 1 Service Desk Analyst at Pomeroy (January 2020 – Current)

Assists UMB with many technical issues from programs not responding, to account unlocks and password resets. Have completed a combined total of 12,000+ calls on various systems and issues.

Created a HTML website designed to help create incident descriptions and also comes with several prewritten work notes for the more common issues. Said program also has a separate page that allows the storage of the previously made incident descriptions.

Computer Programmer Intern at Budget Ninjas LLC (July 2018 – October 2019) (Business Closed) Technologies: Visual Studio, SQL, SSRS, ASP.NET, C#, Telerik, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Azure Devops

Completed a number of projects to enhance their website and created an SSRS report for operations.

For more details please visit: http://dbyrdportfolio.atwebpages.com

Education

<u>Greenville Technical College</u>: Associates degree in Computer Science (spring 2019). Two-time winner of the President's List and three-time winner of Dean's List (3.85 GPA)

<u>LinkedIn Learning</u>: Completed a number of technical courses.

Blue Ridge High School: Graduated 2017

Bonds Career Center: Technical training from 2015 to 2017